[
  {
    "question": "The 12th Circle Chart Music Awards ceremony was held at KSPO Dome in Seoul on February 18, 2023, to recognise the best artists and recordings, primarily based on Circle Music Chart of the year from December 1, 2021, to November 30, 2022. The ceremony was hosted by Doyoung and Miyeon. BTS was the most awarded act with 5 awards, followed by Blackpink with 4.",
    "answer": "4",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "On 6 February 2023 a referendum was held in the Wolayita, Gamo, Gofa, South Omo, Gedeo, and Konso Zones, as well as the Dirashe, Amaro, Burji, Ale, and Basketo special woredas of the Southern Nations, Nationalities, and Peoples' Region (SNNP) of Ethiopia, on whether the included areas should leave SNNP and form their own Region. This referendum follows two previous referendums from 2019 and",
    "answer": "Gamo",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2022–23 Australian bushfire season was the season of summer bushfires in Australia. The outlook for the season was below average in coastal parts of south-eastern Australia due high rainfall associated with the continued La Niña climatic pattern. Elevated fire danger was forecast in Central Australia, inland New South Wales, western Tasmania, southern Queensland and Western Australia, particularly toward the end of the season",
    "answer": "2022–23",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 80th Golden Globe Awards honored the best in film and American television of 2022, as chosen by the Hollywood Foreign Press Association (HFPA). The ceremony was held on January 10, 2023, from The Beverly Hilton in Beverly Hills, California, produced by Dick Clark Productions and the HFPA, and aired live in the United States on NBC and streamed on Peacock. Jerrod Carmichael hosted",
    "answer": "80th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 3rd Critics' Choice Super Awards, presented by the Critics Choice Association and honoring the best in genre fiction film and television. The nominees were announced on February 22, 2023. The winners were announced on March 16, 2023.The Batman led the film field with six nominations, while The Boys, Evil, House of the Dragon, and What We Do in the Shadows, tied for the",
    "answer": "six",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "On 2 April 2023, a bombing occurred in the Street Food Bar №1 café on Universitetskaya Embankment in Saint Petersburg, Russia. Russian military blogger Vladlen Tatarsky, real name Maxim Fomin, died as a result of the explosion and 42 people were injured, 24 of whom were hospitalized, including six in critical conditions.Russia accused Ukraine of being behind the attack and labelled it a \"terrorist",
    "answer": "Russia",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 16th Houston Film Critics Society Awards were announced on February 18, 2023, at the Midtown Arts & Theater Center Houston (MATCH) in Texas. The nominations were announced on January 10, 2023, with The Banshees of Inisherin and Everything Everywhere All at Once leading the nominations with nine each. Both films won the most awards with three each, with Everything Everywhere All at Once",
    "answer": "16th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Music Awards Ceremony (MAC) 2023, presented by Sky Music, was held on 25 and 26 January 2023 to recognize the best in the music of former Yugoslav countries. The ceremony took place at Štark Arena in Belgrade. Following a two-year break due to the COVID-19 pandemic, the third MAC was announced on 27 November 2022. The event for the first time included two nights,",
    "answer": "MAC",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "A constitutional referendum was planned to be held in Mali on 19 March 2023. It was initially scheduled for 9 July 2017. However, in late June it was postponed with no date set, before being revived in mid-April 2021, with a date set of 31 October 2021. Due to the 2021 Malian coup d'état it was indefinitely postponed, with plans for it to be",
    "answer": "Mali",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The SIM Registration Act, officially designated as Republic Act No. 11934 and commonly referred to as the SIM card law, is a Philippine law mandating the registration of SIM cards before activation. Under the measure, mobile device users, must register their SIM cards, whether prepaid or postpaid. The law was enacted intending to curb cybercriminal activities. The law also aims to address issues related",
    "answer": "11934",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Presidential elections are scheduled to be held in the Maldives on Monday 9 September 2023. Incumbent president Ibrahim Mohamed Solih will be seeking re-election, after defeating Speaker of the People's Majlis Mohamed Nasheed in the Maldivian Democratic Party primaries. Former president Abdulla Yameen of the Progressive Party of Maldives and former Minister of Defence and National Security, Mohamed Nazim of the Maldives National Party",
    "answer": "Maldives",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 28th Critics' Choice Awards were presented on January 15, 2023, at the Fairmont Century Plaza Hotel in Los Angeles, California, honoring the finest achievements of filmmaking and television programming in 2022. The ceremony was broadcast on The CW and hosted by Chelsea Handler, taking over the reins from Taye Diggs who had hosted the show consecutively in the previous four years.Like in the",
    "answer": "28th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Local elections are being held in four municipalities in the north of Kosovo on 23 April 2023. They were initially scheduled to be held in December 2022 but were subsequently postoned. The elections are being held in the four Serb-majority municipalities of Leposavić, North Mitrovica, Zubin Potok and Zvečan, located in North Kosovo. The elections are being boycotted by the biggest Serb political party",
    "answer": "four",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 10th Platino Awards, presented by the Entidad de Gestión de Derechos de los Productores Audiovisuales (EGEDA) and the Federación Iberoamericana de Productores Cinematográficos y Audiovisuales (FIPCA), took place on 22 April 2023 at IFEMA Palacio Municipal in Madrid, Spain, to recognize the best in Ibero-American film and television of 2022. The ceremony was hosted by actors Carolina Gaitán, Omar Chaparro and Paz Vega,",
    "answer": "10th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Miss USA 2023 will be the 72nd Miss USA pageant that will be held in 2023 at the Grand Sierra Resort in Reno, Nevada. Morgan Romano of North Carolina will crown her successor at the end of the event. The winner will go on to represent the United States at Miss Universe 2023 competition which is scheduled to be held in El Salvador at",
    "answer": "72nd",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 41st Hong Kong Film Awards presentation ceremony took place at Hong Kong Cultural Centre on 16 April 2023. Nominations were announced on 9 February 2023. The Sparring Partner received 16 nominations most for any film and Detective vs Sleuths, Warriors of Future, and Table for Six with 11 nominations each were second.To My Nineteen Year-Old Self surprisingly won the Best Film award, which",
    "answer": "41st",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "A concert and rally took place on 22 February 2023 at Luzhniki Stadium in Moscow. TASS reported that the rally commemorated Defender of the Fatherland Day. Ukrainska Pravda stated that the date was selected in reference to the starting date of the 2022 Russian invasion of Ukraine, 24 February 2022.RBC reported that President Vladimir Putin was expected to make an appearance, and RIA Novosti",
    "answer": "Moscow",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "On January 19, 2023, the United States hit its debt ceiling, beginning an ongoing debt-ceiling crisis. In response, Janet Yellen, the secretary of the treasury, began enacting temporary \"extraordinary measures\". The crisis is part of a political debate within Congress about federal government spending and the national debt that the U.S. government accrues.In the United States, the debt ceiling is a limit on how",
    "answer": "Congress",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Miss Philippines Earth 2023 was the 23rd edition of the Miss Philippines Earth pageant, it was held at the Toledo City Sports Center in Toledo, Cebu, Philippines on April 29, 2023.At the end of the event, Jenny Ramp of Santa Ignacia, Tarlac crowned Yllana Marie Aduana of Siniloan, Laguna. Her title makes her eligible to represent Philippines at the Miss Earth 2023 competition in",
    "answer": "Philippines",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The removal of Indonesia as FIFA U-20 World Cup 2023 hosts was a political controversy that occurred in March 2023, when FIFA, the world governing body of association football, decided to strip Indonesia of its hosting rights for the 2023 FIFA U-20 World Cup, a youth football tournament that was scheduled to take place in May 2023. The decision was made due to the",
    "answer": "Indonesia",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "This article is about the 2023 flower protests in Russia. There have also been other flower protests, e.g. in Myanmar in 2021 on Suu Kyi's 76th birthday Flower protests are a wave of peaceful, silent protests in Russia, started in January 2023, against the 2022 Russian invasion of Ukraine. Citizens in various cities in Russia choose places that have some connection to Ukraine or",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Chinese military exercises around Taiwan (simplified Chinese: 2023年环台军事演练; traditional Chinese: 2023年環台軍事演練) are a series of ongoing military exercises by the People's Liberation Army (PLA) of the People's Republic of China (PRC) encircling Taiwan (the Republic of China, ROC). On 8 April 2023, the PLA announced the start of \"combat readiness patrols\" and dispatched dozens of fighter jets and several warships toward Taiwan.",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2022, heavy tensions broke out between the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Rwanda, which have led to several alleged attacks by Congolese and Rwandan forces on each other's territory. Rwandan forces have been caught crossing into the DRC multiple times, usually fighting alongside Congolese rebels. The crisis is related to an ongoing offensive beginning in March 2022 by the March 23 Movement",
    "answer": "2022",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 59th Baeksang Arts Awards (Korean: 제59회 백상예술대상) ceremony, organised by Ilgan Sports and JTBC Plus, was held at Incheon Paradise City, Incheon on April 28, 2023, at 17:30 KST. The event was hosted by Shin Dong-yup, Bae Suzy, and Park Bo-gum and was broadcast live in South Korea by JTBC and internationally by TikTok.The annual awards ceremony is one of South Korea's most",
    "answer": "Korean",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Binibining Pilipinas 2023 will be the 59th edition of Binibining Pilipinas to be held on May 28, 2023 at the Smart Araneta Coliseum in Quezon City, Metro Manila, Philippines.At the end of the event, Nicole Borromeo and Chelsea Fernandez will crown their respective successors. Only two titles will be awarded this edition after Binibining Pilipinas Charities, Inc. lost the franchise for Binibining Pilipinas Grand",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 South African National Shutdown was a protest held by the political party EFF on 20 March 2023, the day before Human Rights Day. The EFF called for the resignation of President Cyril Ramaphosa and an end to load-shedding. The leader of the EFF, Julius Malema, warned businesses countrywide to close their doors or risk being looted by them.The Mail and Guardian speculated",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Belgian Cup Final, named Croky Cup after the sponsor, will be the 68th Belgian Cup final and is scheduled to be played on 30 April 2023. KV Mechelen qualified for its seventh Belgian Cup Final on 28 February 2023, and already won the tournament twice, first in 1987 and more recently in 2019. Two days later, Antwerp also qualified, which will be",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The floods in South Africa in February-March 2023 were caused by heavy rainfall as a result of the La Niña weather phenomenon, affecting seven provinces, including Eastern Cape, Northern Cape, Mpumalanga, KwaZulu-Natal, and North West. The floods have caused casualties and damage to homes, businesses, basic infrastructure, roads, bridges and affected crops and livestock. At least twelve people have died across the provinces and",
    "answer": "seven",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Backlash is the upcoming 18th Backlash professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) and livestreaming event produced by WWE. It will be held for wrestlers from the promotion's Raw and SmackDown brand divisions. The event will take place on Saturday, May 6, 2023, at the Coliseo de Puerto Rico José Miguel Agrelot in San Juan, Puerto Rico. This will be the first WWE event held",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Parliamentary elections are scheduled to be held in Slovakia on 30 September 2023 to elect members of the National Council. The 2020 Slovak parliamentary election resulted in a coalition government led by the Ordinary People and Independent Personalities movement. On 15 December 2022 the Slovak government lost a no-confidence vote, and a snap election in 2023 was demanded by the President of Slovakia, Zuzana",
    "answer": "2020",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "An ongoing refugee crisis began in Africa in mid-April 2023 after the outbreak of the 2023 Sudan conflict. By 1 May 2023, an estimated 73,000 to 100,000 people [1] have fled the country, while over 5 million people have been displaced within the country. These included diplomats and citizens and foreign nationals from countries including Somalia, Eritrea, Brazil, the United States, the United Kingdom,",
    "answer": "Africa",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 35th Lo Nuestro Awards were held at the Dade Arena in Miami on February 23, 2023, to recognize the most popular Spanish-language music of 2022. The ceremony will be broadcast on Univisión and will be hosted by television presenters Alejandra Espinoza and Adrián Uribe and singers Sebastián Yatra and Paulina Rubio.The nominees were announced on January 23, 2023, with Colombian singer Sebastián Yatra",
    "answer": "35th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 14th National People's Congress is the current meeting of the legislative branch and, constitutionally, the supreme authority of the People's Republic of China. It convened in Beijing, on 5 March 2023, and is scheduled to continue until March 2028. Elections for the new Congress were held from October 2022 to February 2023. It is scheduled to hold five sessions in this period, occurring",
    "answer": "14th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Various countries and organizations have responded to the 6 February 2023 Turkey–Syria earthquake. At least 105 countries and 16 international organizations pledged support for victims of the earthquake, including humanitarian aid. More than eleven countries provided teams with search and rescue dogs to locate victims under the debris and monetary support was offered as well.However, outreach to Syria was \"less enthusiastic\" than that to",
    "answer": "Turkey",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Advanced Land Observing Satellite 3 (ALOS-3), also called Daichi 3, was a 3-ton Japanese satellite launched on March 7 2023. It was to succeed the optical sensor PRISM (Panchromatic Remote-sensing Instruments for Stereo Mapping) carried on the ALOS satellite, which operated from 2006 to 2011. The ALOS-2 satellite and the future ALOS-4 satellite meanwhile carries a synthetic-aperture radar. The satellite was launched as the",
    "answer": "3-ton",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 6th Hollywood Critics Association Film Awards, presented by the Hollywood Critics Association, took place on the evening of February 24, 2023 at the Beverly Wilshire Hotel, Beverly Hills, while the winners of the 1st Hollywood Critics Association Creative Arts Awards were announced earlier in the day on social media platforms. The nominations for both events were announced on the HCA official YouTube channel",
    "answer": "1st",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 New Year Honours are appointments by some of the 15 Commonwealth realms to various orders and honours to recognise and reward good works by citizens of those countries. The New Year Honours are awarded as part of the New Year celebrations at the start of January and those for 2023 were announced on 30 December 2022. The recipients of honours are displayed",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Census of Nigeria will be a detailed enumeration of the Nigerian population that will be the fifth national census in the country since Independence. It will be the first national census held since 2006. Over 190 Billion Naira (₦) has been allocated for the exercise. A pilot census will be held in July 2022 to get ready for the final census in",
    "answer": "Nigerian",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Rey de Reyes (Spanish for \"2023 King of Kings\") was a professional wrestling tournament and supercard event produced by the Mexican Lucha Libre AAA Worldwide (AAA) promotion. The event was held on February 5, 2023, at Poliforum Zamna in Merida, Yucatan, Mexico. The 2023 event was the 26th Rey de Reyes show and tournament. In the main event match, Sam Adonis defeated",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 New Year Honours in New Zealand were appointments by Charles III in his right as King of New Zealand, on the advice of the New Zealand government, to various orders and honours to reward and highlight good works by New Zealanders, and to celebrate the passing of 2022 and the beginning of 2023. They were announced on 31 December 2022.The recipients of",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Marchetti's constant is the average time spent by a person for commuting each day. Its value is approximately one hour, or half an hour for a one-way trip. It is named after Italian physicist Cesare Marchetti, though Marchetti himself attributed the \"one hour\" finding to transportation analyst and engineer Yacov Zahavi.Marchetti posits that although forms of urban planning and transport may change, and although",
    "answer": "Marchetti",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Live at Bush Hall is a concert film by British rock band Black Country, New Road released on 20 February 2023 through YouTube. It is the first official release since Ants from Up There and the departure of Isaac Wood, the band's vocalist, and consists of recordings from previously unreleased music performed live at Bush Hall, London, over the period of 15–16 December 2022.",
    "answer": "British",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 DFB-Pokal Final will decide the winner of the 2022–23 DFB-Pokal, the 80th season of the annual German football cup competition. The match will be played on 3 June 2023 at the Olympiastadion in Berlin.The winner will host the 2023 edition of the DFL-Supercup at the start of the following season, and will face the champion of the 2022–23 edition of the Bundesliga,",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 75th Directors Guild of America Awards, honoring the outstanding directorial achievement in feature films, documentary, television and commercials of 2022, were presented on February 18, 2023. The ceremony was hosted by Judd Apatow, who previously hosted the ceremonies in 2018, 2020 and 2022. The nominations for the television and documentary categories were announced on January 10, 2023, while the nominations for the feature",
    "answer": "75th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 United Kingdom pupil protests were a series of protests, demonstrations and riots which occurred across secondary schools in the United Kingdom in February and March 2023. The protests were held in opposition to some school rules, especially concerning the use of school toilets during lesson times and rules relating to school uniforms. Videos of the protests were widely circulated on TikTok, with",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 75th Primetime Emmy Awards will honor the best in American prime time television programming from June 1, 2022, until May 31, 2023, as chosen by the Academy of Television Arts & Sciences. The ceremony will be held on September 18, 2023, and will be broadcast in the United States on Fox, with the Creative Arts Emmys to be presented on September 9 and",
    "answer": "75th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Local elections are scheduled to be held in Sri Lanka in 2023. More than 16.6 million Sri Lankans will be eligible to elect 8,711 members to 340 local authorities comprising 24 Municipal Councils, 41 Urban Councils and 275 Divisional Councils. These will be the first elections to be held in Sri Lanka following the major unrest the previous year, which resulted in the ousting",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 All In, also known as All in London at Wembley Stadium, is the upcoming second All In professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) event. It will be the first edition of the event to be produced by All Elite Wrestling (AEW) after the inaugural All In was held independently in September 2018, a few months prior to AEW's formation in January 2019. The event",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 50th ceremony of the Annie Awards, honoring excellence in the field of animation for the year of 2022, was held on February 25, 2023, at the University of California, Los Angeles's Royce Hall in Los Angeles, California in live ceremony after two years as virtual event.The nominees were announced on January 17, 2023, Guillermo del Toro's Pinocchio led the nominations with nine, followed",
    "answer": "50th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 IIHF World Championship Division I is an international ice hockey tournament run by the International Ice Hockey Federation.The Group A tournament is being held in Nottingham, United Kingdom from 29 April to 5 May and the Group B tournament was held in Tallinn, Estonia from 23 to 29 April 2023. Japan won Group B and got promoted while Serbia was relegated after",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 United Nations Climate Change Conference or Conference of the Parties of the UNFCCC, more commonly referred to as COP28, will be the 28th United Nations Climate Change conference, held from November 30th until December 12th, 2023 at the Expo City, Dubai. The conference has been held annually since the first UN climate agreement in 1992. It is used by governments to agree",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The Recovering America's Wildlife Act (RAWA) is a bill in the United States Congress intended to provide funding for the conservation of wildlife in the United States. In the 117th United States Congress, the House of Representatives passed it by 231–190, but although it passed the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works on a bipartisan basis, it never passed the full Senate and",
    "answer": "RAWA",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Berlin 2030 klimaneutral (English: Berlin 2030 climate-neutral) was a citizens' initiative launched in Berlin in 2018. It was the subject of a city-wide referendum scheduled for 26 March 2023, commonly called the Klima-Volksentscheid (English: climate referendum). Voters will be asked whether the Climate Protection and Energy Transition Act of 2016 should be amended. The primary goal of the referendum is to legislate a goal",
    "answer": "Berlin",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Madrid Open (sponsored by Mutua) is a professional tennis tournament to be played on outdoor clay courts at the Park Manzanares in Madrid, Spain from 25 April to 7 May 2023. It will be the 21st edition of the event on the ATP Tour and 14th on the WTA Tour. It is classified as an ATP Tour Masters 1000 event on the",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The Battle of Khartoum is an ongoing battle for control of Khartoum, the capital of Sudan, between the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces (RSF), and the Sudanese Armed Forces. The battle began on 15 April 2023, after the RSF allegedly captured Khartoum International Airport, several military bases, and the presidential palace, starting an escalating series of clashes. It was initially reported that tensions rose in",
    "answer": "Khartoum",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Coupe de France final was a football match between Nantes and Toulouse to decide the winner of the 2022–23 Coupe de France, the 106th season of the Coupe de France.Toulouse won the match 5–1, claiming their first Coupe de France title. It was the city's second title, however, as the unaffiliated predecessor Toulouse FC, which was dissolved in 1967, had won the",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "San Marino is set to participate in the Eurovision Song Contest 2023 in Liverpool, United Kingdom, with \"Like an Animal\" performed by Piqued Jacks. The Sammarinese broadcaster San Marino RTV (SMRTV) organised the national final Una voce per San Marino in order to select the Sammarinese entry for the 2023 contest. The event consisted of over 1000 emerging and 32 established artists competing over",
    "answer": "Liverpool",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 95th Academy Awards was a ceremony held by the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences (AMPAS) on March 12, 2023, at the Dolby Theatre in Los Angeles, which honored films released in 2022.The event was televised in the U.S. by ABC and was produced by Ricky Kirshner and Glenn Weiss. Weiss was also the director. Comedian and late-night talk show host Jimmy",
    "answer": "2022.The",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "On 26 February 2023, a boat carrying migrants sank amidst harsh weather conditions while trying to land on the coast of Steccato di Cutro, a seaside resort village near the town of Crotone, in the region of Calabria in southern Italy. The boat was carrying about 200 migrants when it sank, of whom at least 89 died, including at least 24 children. Eighty-one people",
    "answer": "Crotone",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Nigerian House of Representatives elections were held on 25 February 2023 where voters elected members of the House of Representatives using first-past-the-post voting in all 360 federal constituencies. The last regular House elections for all districts were in 2019. Other federal elections, including the Senate elections and the presidential election, held on the same date while state elections will be held two",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Dark Angel is an American thrash metal band from Downey, California, that formed in 1981. The band's current lineup includes drummer Gene Hoglan, guitarists Eric Meyer and Laura Christine, frontman Ron Rinehart and bassist Mike Gonzalez. In its history, they have gone through many lineup changes, and as of guitarist Jim Durkin's death in March 2023, there are no original members left in the",
    "answer": "American",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2022-2023 Pakistan economic crisis is an ongoing economic crisis and part of 2022-2023 political unrest in Pakistan. It has caused severe economic challenges for months due to which food, gas and oil prices have risen. The Russian invasion of Ukraine has caused fuel prices to rise worldwide. Excessive external borrowings by the country over the years raised the spectre of default, causing the",
    "answer": "2022-2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Miss Grand Ecuador 2023 was the second edition of the Miss Grand Ecuador beauty pageant, held at TC Televisión Studios, Guayaquil. It was originally proposed to be held in January but was postponed to April 15, 2023, for unspecified reasons. Candidates from seven provinces of the country, who qualified for the national pageant via an audition performed virtually earlier in November 2022, competed for",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "All Star Junior Festival 2023 was an interpromotional professional wrestling pay-per-view event organized by New Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW). It was held on March 1, 2023 at Korakuen Hall in Bunkyo, Tokyo, Japan. The event, which was produced by NJPW wrestler Hiromu Takahashi, featured the participation of junior heavyweight wrestlers from over 20 different promotions from around the world. In the main event, NJPW's Master",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1st Hollywood Critics Association Creative Arts Awards, presented by the Hollywood Critics Association, took place on February 24, 2023. The winners were announced on the official HCA Facebook, Instagram and Twitter, while the 6th Hollywood Critics Association Film Awards took place on the same day at the Beverly Wilshire Hotel, Beverly Hills. The nominations were announced on the HCA official YouTube channel and",
    "answer": "1st",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The Nairobi Declaration (Arabic إعــــــــــلان نيـــــــروبي) is an ongoing attempt by a group of South Sudanese military officials led by rebel deputy chief of staff Dickson Gatluak Jock to remove Paul Malong Awan as leader of the opposition South Sudan United Front/Army (SSUF/A). The officers according to the declaration accused Malong of being \"incompetent\" to lead and has not been able to meet his",
    "answer": "Arabic",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Miss Grand South Africa 2023 will be the eighth edition of the Miss Grand South Africa beauty pageant, scheduled to be held on July 22, 2023, at the Atterbury Theatre in South Africa's capital, Pretoria. Thirty-four candidates who qualified for the national pageant through the virtual casting will compete for the title.The winner of the contest will be crowned by Miss Grand South Africa",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Iceberg A-81 is an iceberg that calved from the Brunt Ice Shelf in January 2023. The detachment happened near the British-operated Halley Research Station, which is located only 20 km away from the point of rupture. The iceberg is estimated to measure 1,550 square kilometres (600 sq mi).The iceberg was first spotted on 22 January by the British Antarctic Survey and was later confirmed",
    "answer": "British",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 8th Annual Latin American Music Awards was held on April 20, 2023, to recognize outstanding achievements for artists in the Latin music industry of 2022, voted by the public.The ceremony will took place at the MGM Grand Arena in Las Vegas, United States, and was broadcast simultaneously on Univision, UniMás and Galavisión in the United States, and Canal 5 in México. This marks",
    "answer": "8th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Beginning on 31 July 2022, tensions between Serbia and Kosovo heightened due to the expiration of the eleven-year validity period of documents for cars on 1 August 2022, between the government of Kosovo and the Serbs in North Kosovo. Kosovo, which declared independence in 2008, signed an agreement with Serbia in 2011 that concluded on the use of license plates in North Kosovo. This",
    "answer": "Serbia",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Guatemala City mayoral election will be held on 25 June 2023, to elect the mayor of Guatemala City, Department of Guatemala and thirteen members of the Municipal Council. Incumbent Ricardo Quiñónez Lemus is eligible for another term. Quiñónez of the Unionist Party is running for re-election with the support of Valor. Juan Francisco Solórzano Foppa, a pre-candidate of the Semilla–Winaq–URNG–MAIZ coalition, was",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 30th Hanteo Music Awards (Korean: 30주년 한터뮤직어워즈 2022; RR: 30junyeon Hanteomyujigeowojeu 2022; lit. 30th Anniversary Hanteo Music Awards 2022) ceremony is currently held at Jamsil Arena in Seoul on February 10–11, 2023, to recognise the best artists and recordings, primarily based on Hanteo Chart of the year from January 1 to December 31, 2022. The ceremony is hosted by Eugene, Shin Dong-yup, Hyunsuk",
    "answer": "Korean",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Zerobaseone (Korean: 제로베이스원; RR: Jerobeiseuwon, stylized in all caps; abbreviated as ZB1) is a South Korean boy group formed through Mnet's reality competition Boys Planet in 2023. It is managed by Wake One Entertainment. The group is composed of nine members: Kim Ji-woong, Zhang Hao, Sung Han-bin, Seok Matthew, Kim Tae-rae, Ricky, Kim Gyu-vin, Park Gun-wook and Han Yu-jin. The group will debut in",
    "answer": "Korean",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Las Anod conflict is an ongoing armed conflict between the Somaliland National Army and militias of the Dhulbahante, Majeerteen and Warsangali clans that ensued in Las Anod, the capital of the Sool region. Fighting erupted on February 6 after Somaliland security forces held a violent crackdown on civil protests. On February 8, the supreme Garad of Dhulbahante, Garad Jama Garad Ali, declared",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 Night of Champions is the upcoming 10th Night of Champions professional wrestling pay-per-view (PPV) and livestreaming event produced by the American promotion WWE. It will be held for wrestlers from the promotion's Raw and SmackDown brand divisions. The event is scheduled to be held on Saturday, May 27, 2023, at the Jeddah Super Dome in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia. This will be the",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The Golden Jubilee of Carl XVI Gustaf will be celebrated in 2023 in the Kingdom of Sweden, to mark the 50th anniversary of the accession of King Carl XVI Gustaf on 15 September 1973. He will be the first Swedish king to celebrate a Golden Jubilee. The 500th anniversary of the election of Gustav Vasa as King of Sweden will also marked be during",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The COVID-19 Response Recognition Award is a service award established by the New Zealand government in 2022 to recognise individuals and organisations who contributed to New Zealand’s frontline workforce COVID-19 response. The awards will be distributed from late January 2023, and it is expected that there will be about 80,000 individual recipients.Awards to individuals will take the form of a lapel pin and certificate,",
    "answer": "2022",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "On 26 February 2023, an unidentified person fatally shot two Israeli settlers in their car in Huwara, a town south of Nablus in the Israeli-occupied West Bank. Following the shooting, Israeli settlers carried out revenge attacks on Palestinians, which have killed at least one Palestinian and injured around 100 others. On 7 March, one 49-year-old suspect was killed during an Israeli incursion into Jenin.",
    "answer": "two",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "An indirect presidential election was held in Cuba on 19 April 2023. The election took place following the election to the National Assembly of People's Power on 26 March 2023. The incumbent president, Miguel Díaz-Canel, was eligible for re-election and his candidacy was supported with 459 votes out of 460 valid votes. Two deputies voted blank.Likewise, Salvador Valdés Mesa was re-elected to the position",
    "answer": "Cuba",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Two motions of no confidence in the minority government of Prime Minister Élisabeth Borne were tabled on 17 March 2023 in the French National Assembly. One motion was proposed by a cross-party alliance that included the left-wing NUPES and the regionalist LIOT (introduced by Bertrand Pancher and defended by Charles de Courson); the other by the right-wing populist National Rally (introduced by Marine Le",
    "answer": "Two",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Stardom New Blood 7 (スターダムニューブラッド7, Sutādamunyūburaddo 7) was a professional wrestling event promoted by World Wonder Ring Stardom. The event took place on January 20, 2023, in Tokyo, Japan at the Belle Salle Takadanoba, with limited attendance due in part to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic at the time. The event saw first round matches in a tournament to crown the inaugural New Blood Tag",
    "answer": "7",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The Electoral Commission (An Coimisiún Toghcháin) is an election commission with responsibility for the oversight of all elections in Ireland, including electoral operations, constituency reviews and electoral integrity. It was established in 2023. Prior to its establishment, some of these functions had been carried out by various government departments, statutory agencies and components of the Oireachtas, while other functions are novel to the Commission.",
    "answer": "Ireland",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Municipal elections are set to be held in Israel on 31 October 2023. In accordance with changes made in 2018, election day will be a paid day off work. All municipalities, local councils and regional councils will be up for election, as will their leaders. Top-two runoffs will be held on 14 November in all localities where no leadership candidate won 40% or more",
    "answer": "Israel",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Sakura Genesis was a professional wrestling event promoted by New Japan Pro-Wrestling (NJPW). The event took on April 8, 2023, in Tokyo at Ryōgoku Kokugikan. Previously held under the Invasion Attack name, this was the fourth event to be held under the Sakura Genesis name. The main event saw the 2023 New Japan Cup winner Sanada defeat Kazuchika Okada to win the IWGP World",
    "answer": "NJPW",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2022–23 Toronto Maple Leafs season is the franchise's 106th season in the National Hockey League. On March 27, 2023, the Maple Leafs clinched a playoff spot after the Ottawa Senators defeated the Florida Panthers. On April 29, 2023, the Maple Leafs won their First Round series against the Tampa Bay Lightning, which was the first playoff series win for the franchise since 2004.",
    "answer": "2022–23",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 British Academy Television Awards will be held on 14 May 2023 at the Royal Festival Hall in London, to recognise the excellence in British television of 2022. The nominations were announced on 22 March 2023 alongside the nominations for the 2023 British Academy Television Craft Awards. The nominees for Memorable Moment, voted on by the public, were announced on 18 April 2023.",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Supriyo a.k.a Supriya Chakraborty & Abhay Dang v. Union of India thr. Its Secretary, Ministry of Law and Justice & other connected cases (2023) is an ongoing collection of landmark cases of the Supreme Court of India, which are set to consider whether to extend right to marry and establish a family to queer Indians. A 5-judge Constitution Bench, consisting of Chief Justice of",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Cold Water Flat was an American band formed in 1990 by Paul Janovitz (vocals and guitar), Ted Silva (bass) and Paul Harding (drums) when the trio studied at University of Massachusetts Amherst. Paul Janovitz is the younger brother of Bill Janovitz, lead singer and songwriter of Buffalo Tom. They began playing shows in Boston before Janovitz moved to New York; the group nearly split",
    "answer": "American",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Conveyor belt sushi (Japanese: 回転寿司, Hepburn: kaiten-zushi), also called rotation sushi, is a type of sushi restaurant common in Japan. In Australasia, it is also known as a sushi train. Plates serving the sushi are placed on a rotating conveyor belt that winds through the restaurant and moves past every table, counter and seat. The final bill is based on the number and type",
    "answer": "Japanese",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Many countries allocated relief aid items to southern Africa after Cyclone Freddy, with a main focus on the humanitarian crisis in Malawi. Items included hygiene supplies, food rations, and safe drinking water among other things Total donations reach the millions in USD, and there was also a primary focal point on the historic and ongoing outbreak of Cholera in the region. Several nations also",
    "answer": "Africa",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 40th Robert Awards ceremony, presented by Danish Film Academy on 4 February 2023, to honour the best in Danish film and television of 2022. The ceremony took place at the Tivoli Hotel & Congress Centre in Copenhagen, Denmark and was hosted by actor and comedian Frederik Cilius.Crime drama film Holy Spider won eleven awards out of nominations, including Best Danish Film. It was",
    "answer": "40th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "In April 2023, two sets of classified foreign intelligence documents of the United States began circulating on Twitter, Telegram, and 4chan. Jack Teixeira, an airman first class of the Massachusetts Air National Guard, had allegedly photographed printouts of the documents at his parents' home in Dighton, Massachusetts and posted them to the instant messaging platform Discord on a server named \"Thug Shaker Central\". The",
    "answer": "two",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "SpaceX Crew-7 is planned to be the seventh crewed operational NASA Commercial Crew flight of a Crew Dragon spacecraft, and the eleventh overall crewed orbital flight. The mission is planned for launch on 17 August 2023. The Crew-7 mission would transport four crew members to the International Space Station (ISS). As of August 2022, one NASA astronaut, Jasmin Moghbeli, one ESA astronaut, Andreas Mogensen",
    "answer": "seventh",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2022–23 North American winter was an unusually warm winter for the east and an unusually cold winter for the west in North America, as it occurred across the continent from late 2022 to early 2023. The winter season in North America began at the winter solstice, which occurred on December 21, 2022, and it ended at the March equinox, which occurred on March",
    "answer": "2022–23",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "General elections were held in the British Virgin Islands on 24 April 2023.The initial results indicated that no party had won overall control of the House of Assembly. The incumbent Virgin Islands Party (VIP) won six seats, the National Democratic Party (NDP) and the Progressive Virgin Islands Movement (PVIM) each won three seats, and Progressives United (PU) won a single seat. There followed a",
    "answer": "2023.The",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2023 EuroLeague Playoffs, known as the 2023 Turkish Airlines EuroLeague Playoffs for sponsorship purposes, will be the first postseason portion of the 2022–23 EuroLeague basketball competition. They will begin on 25 April 2023 and are scheduled to be played through 10 May 2023. The top eight finishers in the regular season qualified for the playoffs, which consists of four series of two teams",
    "answer": "2023",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Miss Grand Japan 2023 will be the ninth edition of the Miss Grand Japan beauty pageant, scheduled to be held on July 16, 2023, at the Tokyo FM Hall of the Tokyo FM Center in Chiyoda, Tokyo. Seventeen candidates who qualified for the national pageant via an audition performed in March 2023 will compete for the right to represent Japan at the upcoming edition",
    "answer": "Japan",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The Salvadoran gang crackdown, referred to in El Salvador as the Régimen de Excepción (Spanish for State of Exception) and the Guerra Contra las Pandillas (Spanish for War Against the Gangs), began in March 2022 in response to a crime spike between 25 and 27 March 2022, when 87 people were killed in El Salvador. The Salvadoran government blamed the spike in murders on",
    "answer": "Salvadoran",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The 19th British Academy Video Game Awards were hosted by the British Academy of Film and Television Arts on 30 March 2023 to honour the best video games of 2022. Held at the Queen Elizabeth Hall in London, the ceremony was hosted by esports presenter Frankie Ward, taking over from Elle Osili-Wood who hosted the previous two ceremonies. The ceremony was livestreamed exclusively on",
    "answer": "19th",
    "label": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Since May–June 2022, a series of labour strikes and industrial disputes have occurred in various industries of the United Kingdom's economy as workers walked out over pay and conditions. The strikes took place with rising inflation, and demands for pay increases that would keep pace with this inflation. The strikes began on 15 June 2022 after members of the National Union of Rail, Maritime",
    "answer": "united",
    "label": 0
  }
]